# **Madeline Peters**

## **Software Developer**

SEATTLE, WA (206) 200-0997 madelinepet@hotmail.com linkedin.com/in/madeline-peters https://github.com/madelinepet

Software engineer with experience developing in Python and JavaScript. BA in Geology and a passion for writing readable documentation and determining elegant solutions. Excited about the intersection of science and technology, geospatial analysis, and data structures and algorithms.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS

**Tools/Frameworks**: AWS, Django, Pyramid, ArcGIS, Docker, Github, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL **Other Experience:** Unit/Integration testing, Agile workflow, updating legacy Python code, Jupyter

## **PROJECTS**

#### News\_APII SEPT 2018 | ec2-18-223-109-140.us-east-2.compute.amazonaws.com/

A Pyramid RESTful API with exposed endpoints to organize a user's news feed for current news articles based on user preferences for predominant tone

- Python3, Pyramid, AWS, Bokeh, news\_api, Goose, IBM Watson Tone Analyzer
- Wrote Archives model and Visuals View, wrote README.md
- github.com/PythonMidterm/news\_api

## Fozzie Web-Builder | APRIL 2018 | http://fozzie-web-builder.herokuapp.com/

Application that dynamically renders HTML file for user based on specifications

- JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Heroku
- github.com/Team-Fozzie/Fozzie-s-Website-Builder-Server

#### CLI Restaurant | AUG 2018 | github.com/madelinepet/snakes-cafe

A mock POS system that reads from a CSV with a menu, order total, and receipt

Python3

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Code Fellows | TA

NOV 2018- PRESENT, SEATTLE, WA

- Guided students towards solutions
- JavaScript, SMACSS, jQuery, Express
- Graded student work and worked closely with instructor

#### **REI | Sales Specialist**

APRIL 2017 - FEB 2018, SEATTLE, WA

- Implemented customer-focused solutions and participated in sales
- Became familiar with company-related software
- Upheld the values of the company while making independent decisions

## **Additional Experience Provided Upon Request**

## **EDUCATION**

Code Fellows | Seattle, WA | MARCH 2018 - OCT 2018

• Certificate - Advanced Software Development in Full-Stack Python

Whitman College | Walla Walla, WA | AUG 2012 - SEPT 2016

B.A. in Geology with Anthropology minor